Crime is a disease. Meet the cure.
Cobra is a action, crime, thriller film directed by George P. Cosmatos.
A tough-on-crime street cop must protect the only surviving witness
to a strange murderous cult with far reaching plans.
Marion 'Cobra' Cobretti, played by Sylvester Stallone.
Ingrid, played by Brigitte Nielsen.
Sergeant Gonzales, played by Reni Santoni.
Night Slasher, played by Brian Thompson.
Nancy Stalk, played by Lee Garlington.
Captain Sears, played by Art LaFleur.
Cobra is a 1986 American action film directed by George P.
Cosmatos and written by Sylvester Stallone, who stars in the title role.
The film, loosely based on the 1974 novel A Running Duck by Paula Gosling (later published as Fair Game and
filmed under that title in 1995), co-stars Reni Santoni, Brigitte Nielsen and Andrew Robinson.
Cobra follows Los Angeles police Lt.
Marion "Cobra" Cobretti, who investigates a string of violent crimes and also
protects Ingrid Knudsen, a witness targeted by the perpetrators.
Cobra is the final film which featured the collaboration between Stallone and Nielsen after Rocky IV (1985) until Creed II (2018), and
the only film the pair are both featured in while married to one another in real life, before their divorce a year later.
The script was largely inspired by Stallone's original
script for Beverly Hills Cop (1984).
Cobra was released to generally negative reviews with criticism on its excessive violence and overuse of
genre tropes, but it was a box office success and has since been considered a cult classic.
The film explores themes of showdown, street gang,
resistance, psychopath, prosecution.
The tone is intense.